# LAVISH BANSAL

**R&D Engineer** 

### **Contact**

#### **Address**

Whitefield, Bengaluru, KA, 560066

#### **Phone**

9888207237

#### E-mail

lavish.bansal0795@gmail.com

### **Skills**

Strong fundamentals in data Science field

Hands-on working experience on ML models such as Linear regression, Logistic regression, Decision Tree

Experience in Exploratory data analysis using matplotlib, scikit learn, pandas, etc. in Jupyter notebook

Hands-on working experience on Text Mining and Natural Language processing (NLP). – BOW TFIDF, Word2Vec

Working experience on Scikit learn, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlip, seaborn, NLTK

Working Experience in Python, Java

A Passionate Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in Data Science, who seeks for a challenging role in IT Sector, where the competent technical skills, verbal skills and talent can be used to bring the organization, a sharper edge within the industry besides ensuring personal growth. Skilled in machine learning, statistics, automation, problem solving and programming

# **Work History**

#### 2021-03 -

# **BridgeTree** – R&D Engineer

Current

• Project: Product Placement (Proof of Concept)

**Overview:** This involves detection products in a supermarket using YOLO model and then finding out the placement of each product.

Role: Developer Model: YOLOv4

Data Source: Google Images

Technologies & Tools: Python, Google Colab

# 2018-05 -

# **MetricStream - MTS (Member Technical Staff)**

2021-03

• Project: Text Summarization System

**Overview:** Extraction-based summarization:

This model creates a summary of the long document by considering top-n phrases and sentences that relay the most useful information from the original text

**Business Use Case:** PDMS app provide customers a space to efficiently keep policies/procedures and customers create their policies and have to write summary for the created policy as well which was a very tedious job for them to do.

Role: Developer

**Libraries:** NLTK, Scikit Learn, Gensim **Model:** Word2Vec, Text Rank Algorithm

Data Source: API

Project: Answering System of similar question

**Overview**: This system identifies the similar question asked by different client in shared location like confluence page and refer the already available solution in the page.

**Business Use Case:** PM has to address number of queries and questions asked by either customer or by GS team. Most of the time questions were repetitive and to address their queries more effectively and in lesser time, we have implemented this solution

**Role: Developer** 

Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, NLTK, Scikit Learn

Model: Logistic regression

Knowledge on SVM, KNN Models

Knowledge on Ensembles model like Random Forest, GBDT, XGBoost

Knowledge on Principle component analysis (PCA) and t-SNE

#### **Software**

**Python** 

Very Good

Core Java

Very Good

# Languages

English

Hindi

Punjabi

Native

Data Source: Confluence page

Project: Automated MLS Testing Tool

**Overview:** R&D tests its releases to ensure that the apps are MLS enabled. The tests are manual and consume, based on size of the app, anywhere from 2-15 days of effort and additional 1-2 days to setup MLS for any of the app. This tool generates a report which points out the potential bugs in application and this reduces the testing effort to less than 2 hours

Role: Developer

Technologies & Tools: Java

# **Other Projects**

#### **House Price prediction Model**

**Overview:** Predicting house prices dataset for analysis of Boston house dataset and finally running Linear Regression Model and Predicting the

house prices.

Libraries: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, SciPy, Seaborn

Model: Random Forest Regressor model

Data Source: Kaggle

# **Education**

# 2013-2017 Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science and Engineering

Shaheed Bhagat Singh State Technical Campus, Ferozepur (Punjab

Technical University) – Punjab Graduated with 78.4% marks

#### 2012-2013 Intermediate: Science

D.N Model Sr. Sec - Moga, Punjab Graduated with 83.2% marks

#### 2010-2011 Secondary: Science

Geeta Bhawan Public School - Moga, Punjab

Graduated with 90% marks